Finding Aid for the George Walden Savage Papers LSC.0790
UCLA Library Special Collections
George Walden Savage papers
1914-1961
UCLA Library Special Collections
Savage, George Walden
LSC.0790
7.2 linear feet (8 document boxes and 4 oversize flat boxes)
George Walden Savage (1903-1961) was a journalist and newspaper publisher for various newspapers around the Owens valley in California. He also served as secretary of the highway commission (1948-49), was a member of the Governor's Public Information Committee (1959-60) and president of the San Bernardino Chamber of Commerce (1960-61). The collection consists of newspaper clipplings and scrapbooks containing correspondence, clippings, photographs, and related printed material.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Mary Savage.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942337323606533
Biography
Savage was born on June 27, 1903 in Dennison, Ohio; became a journalist and newspaper publisher in California; was owner-publisher of the Inyo-Independent (Independence, California), Progress Citizen (Lone Pine, California), Inyo Register (Bishop, California), 1933-45, and South Pasadena Review, 1946-47; was manager of the Inland Printing and Engraving Company, San Bernardino, California, 1949-61; he also served as secretary of the highway commission (1948-49), member of the Governor's Public Information Committee (1959-60), and president of the San Bernardino Chamber of Commerce (1960-61); he died on September 15, 1961 in San Bernardino.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of newspaper clippings and scrapbooks containing correspondence, clippings, photographs, and related printed material concerning Savage's career as a journalist and newspaper publisher and the Japanese War Relocation Center at Manzanar, California.
Organization and Arrangement
This collection is organized by type of material.
Journalists -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Scrapbooks.; Publishers and publishing -- California, Southern -- Archives.; Savage, George Walden -- Archives
- Newspaper clippings, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Death Valley ephemera, 1937-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Memorabilia, 1937-1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspaper clippings, 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folders 1-5)
- Scrapbook with Claremont Courier clippings, 1923-1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspaper clippings, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Newspaper clippings, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Newspaper clippings, 1933-40 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Script of operetta "Our American Cousin" by Jones and Clokey, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Manuscripts, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Congressional record containing editorial by George W. Savage, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- First editions of Life Overseas Edition, Time Pacific Edition, Newsweek Hawaii, The New Pacific, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Pamphlets and magazines, 1925-1961 (Box 4, Folders 6-7)
- Correspondence: Memorial letters on George W. Savage's death, 15 September 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Correspondence: Letters of condolence to Mrs. Mary Savage, on death of George W. Savage, September 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Visit of Germans from Offenburg, Germany in San Bernardino, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Personal, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Personal, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Personal, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Personal, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Personal, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Personal, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Personal, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- World War II Ephemera, 1943-1961 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Photographs, ca. 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Appointments book, 1948 (Box 6)
- Photograph album: A Visit to the Armor Combat Training Center, 1948 (Box 6)
- Scrapbook with newspaper clippings, 1922 (Box 6)
- Photograph album: "Visit of George W. Savage, 28th Joint Civilian Orientation Conference, The United States Army Infantry Center", 8-12 May 1959 (Box 6)
- Notebook: Navy Lieutenant George W. Savage, 8-12 May 1959 (Box 6)
- Guest Book: U.S.S. Helena, 1952 (Box 6)
- Correspondence, photographs, documents: Navy, 1949-1952 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Manuscript: Japanese relocation to Manzanar, undated (Box 7, Folders 1-3)
- Correspondence, clippings: Manzanar, 1942 (Box 8, Folders 1-5)
- Scrapbooks, 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Box 10, Box 11, Box 12)
- Magazines: Articles about Manzanar, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 1)